amateurtraveler.com 2019-08-30

# Privacy Policy - Amateur Traveler

At Amateur Traveler, your privacy is very important to us. We have a few fundamental principles that we follow. Read this carefully, so you know your rights.

**Principles**

Your privacy is very important to us. At Amateur Traveler we have a few fundamental principles that we follow:

We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it.  
We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.  
We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the on-going operation of our site.  
Frankly we are just too busy to do anything creepy with your personal information, even if we wanted to… and we don’t.

**Website Visitors**

Like most website operators, Amateur Traveler collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Amateur Traveler’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Amateur Traveler’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Amateur Traveler may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Amateur Traveler also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on our blogs. Amateur Traveler only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below.

**Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information**

Certain visitors to Amateur Traveler’s websites choose to interact with Amateur Traveler in ways that require Amateur Traveler to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Amateur Traveler gathers depends on the nature of the interaction.

For example, we ask visitors who comment on our blog to provide a username and email address. Those who wish to receive Amateur Traveler updates via email, we collect their emails. In each case, Amateur Traveler collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Amateur Traveler. Amateur Traveler does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

More specifically:

  * If you subscribe to our newsletter, we need an email or we can’t send it.
  * If you leave a comment we collect an email so we can respond to you in private when needed or so you can get updates to your comment.

**Aggregated Statistics**

Amateur Traveler may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Amateur Traveler may monitor the most popular pages on the Amateur Traveler.com site or use spam screened by the Akismet service to help identify spam. Amateur Traveler may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Amateur Traveler does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

**Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information**

Amateur Traveler discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Amateur Traveler’s behalf or to provide services available at Amateur Traveler’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others.

More specifically:

  * We use mailchimp.com to send emails so when you sign up for an email newsletter your email get stored and sent from them.
  * We collect emails via the HappyFox Chat widget so you can send us a message. Those emails don’t get added to a list but do get sent to us as a return email address.

Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Amateur Traveler’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Amateur Traveler will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone.

Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Amateur Traveler discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Amateur Traveler believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Amateur Traveler, third parties or the public at large.

If you are a registered fir the Amateur Traveler newsletter and have supplied your email address, Amateur Traveler will occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Amateur Traveler. We primarily use our blog to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. Honestly we would like to send more email than we currently do, but are pretty busy. It’s not that we don’t love you.

If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish the content (not not the email address) in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. We usually don’t include people’s full names when we  do publish comments, unless they have chosen to do so. Amateur Traveler takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

**Opting Out**

If you desire to unsubscribe from our mailing list simply use the unsubscribe link in enervating newsletter.

If you want to have your user record and comments deleted from the website, contact us and we would be willing although sad to do so: email host [at] amateurtraveler.com .

**Cookies**

Cookie’s are tasty snacks and if you want to send us cookies, send chocolate chip cookies.

A cookie is also is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Amateur Traveler uses cookies to help Amateur Traveler identify and track visitors, their usage of Amateur Traveler website, and their website access preferences. Amateur Traveler visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Amateur Traveler’s website, with the drawback that certain features of Amateur Traveler’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**Business Transfers**

If Amateur Traveler, or substantially all of its assets were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Amateur Traveler goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Amateur Traveler may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

**Ads**

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by Amateur Traveler and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. We do not know the policy of any of our advertisers to chocolate chip cookies, but we assume they are also in favor or them.

**Privacy Policy Changes**

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Amateur Traveler may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Amateur Traveler’s sole discretion. Amateur Traveler encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

We assume that if you read this far in our privacy policy your are a detailed oriented person, are really paranoid or are a lawyer (which may be redundant to the first two statements).
